Toni Morrison Papers, 1917-2015: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1953-2015; 35 boxes
  - Lebowitz, Fran, 2000-2011; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 15)
  - LeClerc, Paul, 2004-2006; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 16)
  - Lee, Chang-Rae, 2004-2009; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 17)
  - Lee, Spike, 1986-1999; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 18)
  - Leenders, Rada, 2004-2007; 1 folder (Box 82, Folder 19)
  - Leland, Christopher T., 1983-1987; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Lemaître, Pascal, 2005-2006; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Lewis, Robin, 1989-1998; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Lewis, Shirley A. R., 2006-2009; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Lieberman, Erez, 2002-2003; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Lightfoot, Betty, 2003-2012; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Lish, Gordon, 1986-1987; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - Loggia, Marjorie, 1985-1986; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - Lombard, Rudy, 1980-2014; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - Love, Edward, 1984-1988; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 10)
    Includes slides.
  - Lubiano, Wahneema, 1991-1999; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 11)
  - M, 1970-2012; 4 folders (Box 83, Folder 12-15)
  - Ma, Yo Yo, 1995; 1 folder (Box 83, Folder 16)
  - Madden, Chris, 1999-2012; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - Maguire, Mary, undated; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Maillard, Carol, 1984-2012; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Malkiel, Nancy and Burton, 1993-2009; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Mandela, Nelson, 1993; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Massiah, Louis, 1998-2015; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - Matsutsuyu, Emiko, 1996-2000; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - Mayes, Janis, 1988-2011; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 8)
  - Maynard, Valerie, 1988-1997; 1 folder (Box 84, Folder 9)
  - McBride, Dwight, 1990-2008; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - McCluskey, John, 1984-1989; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - McCourt, Frank, 2008; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - McCoy, Maureen, 1987-2000; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - McDonald, Erroll and Klara Glowczewska, 2001-2010; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - McFadden, Bernice, 2000-2011; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - McGowan, Tara, 1993, 2002; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - McKay, Nellie, 1981-1990; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - McKayle, Donald, 1981-1988; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - McMillan, Terry, 1986-1990; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 10)
  - McPherson, James, 1987-1991; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 11)
  - Medina, Kate, 1988-2008; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 12)
  - Merwin, W.S., 1988-1989; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 13)
  - Middleton, Joyce, 1990-1994; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 14)
  - Milanés, Cecilia Rodríguez, 1989-2008; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 15)
  - Milford, Nancy, 1988-1993; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 16)
  - Miller, Robin J., 2004; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 17)
  - Millett, Kate, 1990; 1 folder (Box 85, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Cards, 1989-2015; 5 folders (Box 86, Folder 1-5, Box 87, Folder 1-3)
  - Miscellaneous Fire Damaged Letters, 1965-1985; Fire-damaged correspondence in bound album. 1 folder (Box 115, Folder 1)
    Includes correspondence with Alan Rinzler and Ellin K. Roberts about The Bluest Eye; correspondence related to Morrison's position as a textbook editor at L.W. Singer Company; correspondence from Green & Hillman lawyers about a Song of Solomon movie deal and interview with the American Audio Prose Library; and correspondence with Donald McKayle, Capitol Rep Theatre, Gilbert Moses, and others regarding Dreaming Emmett.
  - Miscellaneous Invitations, 1985-2000; 1 folder (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Mondale, Joan, 1979; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Moore, Beatrice Duncan, 1996-2008; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - Morgenroth, Kate, 1998-2001; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Mori, Aoi, 2001-2009; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Morrison, Cecilia Rouse, 2000-2012; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Morrison, Harold and Claudette, 1992-1993; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Morrison, Harold Ford, 1979-2011; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Morrison, Mavis, 1973-1994; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - Morrison, Nidal and Safa, 2002-2009; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - Morrison, Slade, 1981-2007; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 10)
  - Moses, Gilbert, 1986-1993; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 11)
  - Moskin, J. Robert, 1988; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 12)
  - Mosley, Walter, 1998-2005; 1 folder (Box 88, Folder 13)
  - Muldoon, Paul and Jean Hanff Korelitz, 1993-2007; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - N, 1971-2006; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Nabokov, Ivan, 1988-2006; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Nagy, Bob and Vincy, 1998-2009; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Navasky, Victor, 1986-2005; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Naylor, Gloria, 1984-1986; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Nesbit, Lynn, 1989; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - Newhouse, Donald and Susan, 1987-2007; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - Newhouse, Elyse and Michael, 1992-1995; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - Nick, Larry, 1988-2003; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - Noormohamed, Taleeb, 1996-1999; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 11)
  - Norman, Jessye, 1990-2015; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 12)
  - O, 1981-2005; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 13)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol, 1983-2008; 1 folder (Box 89, Folder 14)
  - Obama, Barack and Michelle, 2009-2012; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Obama Campaign, 2008-2014; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Oe, Kenzaburo, 1996-1997; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Ohkoso, Yoshiko, circa 1993-2008; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Ondaatje, Michael, 1994-2002; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Ostriker, Alicia and Jeremiah, 1996-2000; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Owens, Joan Murrell and Frank, 1984-2011; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - P, 1970-2015; 2 folders (Box 90, Folder 8-9)
  - Pagels, Elaine, 1993-1995; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - Painter, Nell, 1988-2013; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 11)
  - Paladino, Vita, 2004-2012; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 12)
  - Pardini, Patti, 1984-1987; 1 folder (Box 90, Folder 13)
  - Paquet-Deyris, Anne-Marie, 1988-2007; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Patterson, Louise and MaryLouise, 1987-2000; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Pelosi, Nancy, 2012; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - Pemberton, Gayle, 1987-1999; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Pierce-Baker, Charlotte, 1990-1998; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Pinckney, Darryl, 2002; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Piñon, Nélida, 1988-1998; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 7)
  - Pinter, Harold, 2005; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Plimpton, George, 1992; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - Pohlig, Ulrike, 1987-1992; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - Polinsky, Eugene, 2001-2014; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 11)
  - Powell, Marc and Ivy, 2004-2008; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 12)
  - Price, Reynolds, 1974-2008; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 13)
  - Price, Richard, 1985-1990; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 14)
  - Q, 1970-2005; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 15)
  - Quinn, Alice, 1993-2003; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 16)
  - R, 1970-2005; 2 folders (Box 91, Folder 17-18)
  - Raboteau, Albert and Julia, 1993; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 19)
  - Rampersad, Arnold, 1988-2006; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 20)
  - Reagon, Bernice Johnson, 1984-2006; 1 folder (Box 91, Folder 21)
  - Reed, Ishmael, 1977-2007; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Reid, Harry, 2012; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Reidy, Carolyn, 2003-2006; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Remnick, David, 1998-2009; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Rhinehart, Doug, 1988; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Richardson, Yvette, 1978-1998; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 6)
  - Rigolot, Carol and François, 1990-2002; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 7)
  - Riley, Mary, 2011; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 8)
  - Roberts, Mary, 1989-1990; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 9)
  - Robinson, Lisa, 1995-2009; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 10)
  - Roediger, Dave, 1994-1997; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 11)
  - Roth, Philip, 1985; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 12)
  - Rouse, Carolyn and Glenn, 2012; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 13)
  - Rouse, Lorraine and Carl, 2001-2015; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 14)
  - Rudenstine, Neil and Angelica, 1988-2005; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 15)
  - Rushdie, Salman, 1994-2000; 1 folder (Box 92, Folder 16)
  - S, 1970-2005; 2 folders (Box 92, Folder 17-18)
  - S, 1970-2005; 2 folders (Box 93, Folder 1-2)
  - Said, Edward, 1992; 1 folder (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Samuels, Wilfred D., 1988-2001; 1 folder (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Sanchez, Sonia, 1993-2014; 1 folder (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Saunders, Paula Redick and George, 1988-2015; 1 folder (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Saunders, Raymond, 1989-1995; 1 folder (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Saunders, Ronnie, 1987-1994; 1 folder (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Sawyer, Diane, 2005; 1 folder (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Scearce, J. Mark, 2002-2003; 1 folder (Box 93, Folder 10)
  - Schwartz, Leonard, 1997-2008; 1 folder (Box 93, Folder 11)
  - Scrivanich, Olivia Brooks, 1984-2008; 1 folder (Box 93, Folder 12)
  - Seward, Adrienne Lanier, 2001; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Shalit, Willa, 1986-2005; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Shapiro, Harold and Vivian, 1990-2001; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Shestakova, Tatyana, 2003-2008; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Showalter, Elaine, 1990-1992; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - Silko, Leslie Marmon, 1984-1999; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Simmons, Ruth, 1988-2012; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - Simone, Nina, 1995; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Smalls, Alexander, 1995-2000; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - Smart, Aisha Karefa, 1988-2007; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - Smart, Gloria Karefa, 1986-2014; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 11)
  - Smart, Kali-Ma Karefa, 1995-2010; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 12)
  - Smiley, Tavis, 2006; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 13)
  - Smith, Barbara, 1985-1988; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 14)
  - Smith, Liz, 2008-2010; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 15)
  - Soyinka, Wole, 1994; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 16)
  - Spillers, Hortense, 1975-1989; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 17)
  - Spivak, Gayatri, 1995-2006; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 18)
  - Stansell, Christine, 1989-1995; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 19)
  - Stein, Sol, 2003-2004; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 20)
  - Stewart, Connie Jellison, 1984-2010; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 21)
  - Strick, Joe, 1985-2001; 1 folder (Box 94, Folder 22)
  - Strouse, Jean, 1981-1990; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Suber, Gloria, 1981-2009; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Swain, Carol, 1989-1997; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - T, 1970-2005; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Talese, Nan, 1991-2002; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Talley, Andre Leon, 2012; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Tan, Amy, 1991-1995; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Taylor, Clyde, 1977-2004; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Taylor, Joseph, 1994; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - Taylor, Susan, 1987-1995; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 10)
  - Thelwell, Ekwueme Michael, 1992-2000; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 11)
  - Theroux, Alexander, 2004-2011; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 12)
  - Thomas, Marlo and Phil Donohue, 2002-2005; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 13)
  - Thompson, Anne E., circa 1989-2005; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 14)
  - Tilghman, Shirley, 2006-2008; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 15)
  - Tomlin, Lily, 2001; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 16)
  - Traylor, Eleanor, 1999-2001; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 17)
  - Treuer, David, 1992-2015; 1 folder (Box 95, Folder 18)
  - Treuer, Robert, 1992-1998; 1 folder (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Troupe, Margaret Porter and Quincy, 1989-2000; 1 folder (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Tubert, Susana, 2000-2010; 1 folder (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Unknown Sender, 1970-2005; 4 folders (Box 96, Folder 4-7)
  - Unknown Sender, 1970-2005; 2 folders (Box 97, Folder 1-2)
  - Urban, Amanda "Binky", undated; 1 folder (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - V, 1970-2005; 1 folder (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - Velasquez, Chloe, 1984-2015; 2 folders (Box 97, Folder 5-6)
  - Velasquez, Sage, 2006-2007; 1 folder (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - Verdelle, A.J., 1995-2012; 1 folder (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - Vereen, Ben, 1998-2000; 1 folder (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - W, 1970-2005; 2 folders (Box 98, Folder 1-2)
  - Wall, Cheryl, 1985-2012; 1 folder (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Walker, Alice, 1978-1995; 1 folder (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Walker, B.B., 1992-1997; 1 folder (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Walker, Joan and Lorenzo, 1980-2015; 3 folders (Box 98, Folder 6-8)
  - Wang, Anne, 1987-1988; 1 folder (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - Wangerin, Walter, 1996-2011; 1 folder (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - West, Cornel, 1992; 1 folder (Box 98, Folder 11)
  - White, Armond, 1997-2000; 1 folder (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - White, Marvina, 1992-2001; 1 folder (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Wiesel, Elie, 1993-2002; 1 folder (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Wilcox, Jim, 1985-1997; 1 folder (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Wilentz, Sean, 1993-1999; 1 folder (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Williams, C.K., 1998-2002; 1 folder (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Williams, John, 1985-1996; 1 folder (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - Williams, Patricia J., 1998; 1 folder (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Williams, Sherley Anne, 1986; 1 folder (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - Willis, Anne, 1978-2011; 1 folder (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - Willis, Avery, 1987-2015; 1 folder (Box 99, Folder 11)
  - Willis, Goreleigh, 1988-2012; 1 folder (Box 99, Folder 12)
  - Willis, Sr., John, 1982-1984; 1 folder (Box 99, Folder 13)
  - Willis, John, 1986-1989; 1 folder (Box 99, Folder 14)
  - Willis, Saundra, 1993-2010; 1 folder (Box 99, Folder 15)
  - Wilson, Robert, 1999-2003; 1 folder (Box 99, Folder 16)
  - Winfrey, Oprah, 1990-2010; 2 folders (Box 99, Folder 17-18)
  - Winters, Heather, 2006-2008; 1 folder (Box 99, Folder 19)
  - Wofford, George, 1984-1989; 1 folder (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Wofford, Lois Yvonne Bell, 1996, 2000; 1 folder (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Wofford, Misha, 1992-2001; 1 folder (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Wofford, Ramah, 1977-1986; 1 folder (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - Wofford, Raymond, 1988-1992; 1 folder (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Wofford, Tammara, 1993-2006; 1 folder (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Wolitzer, Hilma, 1987-1991; 1 folder (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Woods, Donnie, 1977-1988; 1 folder (Box 100, Folder 8)
  - Woods, Joyce Ann, 1981-1992; 1 folder (Box 100, Folder 9)
  - Woods, Stephanie, 1994-2007; 1 folder (Box 100, Folder 10)
  - X, Y, Z, 1970-2005; 1 folder (Box 100, Folder 11)
  - Yoshida, Michiko, 1991-2003; 1 folder (Box 100, Folder 12)
  - Zinsser, William, 1986; 1 folder (Box 100, Folder 13)
- Series 3: Random House, 1971-1982; 2 boxes
  Consists of memos and correspondence, contracts, publicity material and press clippings relating to projects Morrison worked on as an editor at Random House. Includes typescript material from The Greatest: My Own Story by Muhammad Ali, "Little Man, Little Man: A Children's Story" by James Baldwin, various works by Toni Cade Bambara, Angela Davis: An Autobiography, and They Came Before Columbus by Ivan Van Sertima.
  - Ali, Muhammad, 1973-1975; 1 folder (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Baldwin, James, 1973-1975; 1 folder (Box 101, Folder 2)
  - Bambara, Toni Cade, 1971-1978; 2 folders (Box 101, Folder 3-4)
  - The Black Book, 1974-1978; 1 folder (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - Chinweizu, 1977-1978; 1 folder (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - Cosby, Bill, 1976-1977; 1 folder (Box 101, Folder 7)
  - Davis, Angela, 1971-1973; 2 folders (Box 101, Folder 8-9)
  - Diamond, Stanley, 1975-1979; 1 folder (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Forrest, Leon, undated; 1 folder (Box 102, Folder 2)
  - Lester, Julius, 1977-1978; 1 folder (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - McPherson, James, 1978-1979; 1 folder (Box 102, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1972-1978; 1 folder (Box 102, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous MS Inquiries, 1977-1982; 1 folder (Box 102, Folder 6)
  - "Toni Morrison" Letterhead Stationery, undated; 1 folder (Box 102, Folder 7)
  - Van Sertima, Ivan, 1971-1981; 4 folders (Box 102, Folder 8-11)
- Series 4: Toni Cade Bambara Posthumous Publications, 1984-2002; 6 boxes
  Drafts, proofs, and publication material relating to two works by Bambara edited and published posthumously by Morrison: Deep Sightings and Rescue Missions: Fiction, Essays, and Conversations (1996) and Those Bones Are Not My Child (working title: Ground Cover) (1999).
  - Deep Sightings and Rescue Missions, circa 1996; 5 folders (Box 116, Folder 1-5)
    Photocopied typescript and computer printouts, with corrections. Folder 5 includes a note from Nara Nahm at Pantheon Books, dated June 12, 1996.
  - Those Bones are Not My Child, 1984-2002; 6 boxes (1 partial)
    - Those Bones are Not My Child Draft Fragments, circa 1984-1995; portions of 2 boxes
      Research material, typescript and printout drafts, with corrections. Folder 1 includes a letter from Bambara to Joan [Benham], dated October 25, 1984.
      - Those Bones are Not My Child Draft Fragments, circa 1984-1995; 2 folders (Box 116, Folder 6-7)
      - Those Bones are Not My Child Draft Fragments, circa 1984-1995; 2 folders (Box 117, Folder 1-2)
    - Those Bones are Not My Child Draft (as Ground Cover), 1997 February 12; Photocopy. portions of 2 boxes
      Pages 1-1327.
      - Those Bones are Not My Child Draft (as Ground Cover) Pages 1-723, 1997 February 12; 4 folders (Box 117, Folder 3-6)
      - Those Bones are Not My Child Draft (as Ground Cover)Pages 724-1327, 1997 February 12; 4 folders (Box 118, Folder 1-4)
    - Those Bones are Not My Child Prologue Drafts, undated; Printout and photocopy. 1 folder (Box 118, Folder 5)
    - Those Bones are Not My Child Draft, undated; Printout and photocopy, corrected. portions of 2 boxes
      Pages 1-1327. With letter from Toni Morrison to Joan [Benham].
      - Those Bones are Not My Child Draft Pages 1-195, undated; 1 folder (Box 118, Folder 6)
      - Those Bones are Not My Child Draft Pages 207-1327, undated; 5 folders (Box 119, Folder 1-5)
    - Those Bones are Not My Child Re-typed Pages, 1998 August 28; 1 folder (Box 119, Folder 6)
      With letters from Joan Benham to Toni Morrison and Erroll McDonald.
    - Those Bones are Not My Child Proofs, 1999 April 10; 4 folders (Box 120, Folder 1-4)
      Pages i-viii, 1-670.
    - Those Bones are Not My Child Advance Copy, 1999; 1 folder (Box 120, Folder 5)
      Signed by Toni Morrison on front cover, dated June 23, 1999.
    - Those Bones are Not My Child Publisher Correspondence, 1998-2000; 1 folder (Box 121, Folder 1)
      Faxes and letters relating to manuscript corrections, book design, and publicity.
    - Those Bones are Not My Child Press, 1999-2002; 1 folder (Box 121, Folder 2)
- Series 5: Academic Career, 1984-2011; 12 boxes
  This series is arranged into three subseries following the original groupings of the material.
  SUNY Albany and Princeton University material consists of administrative files. Teaching files include all material relating to courses taught by Morrison at SUNY Albany, Princeton, and the University of Chicago, as well as both academic and administrative files from the Atelier program Morrison ran at Princeton.
  This material is stored off site. Please allow 24-48 hrs for retrieval.
  - Subseries 5A: SUNY Albany, 1984-1989; 3 boxes (1 partial)
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    Consists of files relating to Morrison's position as Albert Schweitzer Professor of the Humanities, which she held from 1984 to 1988, including administrative memos and database printouts, material concerning the Birth of Black Cinema conference she co-sponsored, and files concerning the post-graduate Schweitzer Humanities Fellows, Elmaz Abinader and Charlotte Nekola.
    - The Birth of Black Cinema, 1986-1988; 3 folders (Box 103, Folder 1-3)
    - Colia Clark Advisory Panel, 1986; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 16)
      This material is closed until 2061.
    - Correspondence, 1985-1989; 1 folder (Box 103, Folder 4)
    - New York State Writer's Institute, 1984-1986; 1 folder (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - Schweitzer Chair Personnel, 1985-1986; 1 folder (Box 114, Folder 17)
    - Schweitzer Chair Program, 1984-1988; 1 folder (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - Schweitzer DBASE Program Files, 1986; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Schweitzer Fellows, 1985-1986; 1 folder (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - Schweitzer Reports, 1985-1986; 2 folders (Box 104, Folder 3-4)
  - Subseries 5B: Princeton University, 1986-2011; 3 boxes
    Consists of files relating to Morrison's position as the Robert E. Goheen Professor in the Council of Humanities, which she held from 1989 to 2006, including administrative and departmental files as well as other events and projects.
    This subseries is temporarily closed pending review for restricted materials.
    - 110 Dickinson move to 185, 2002; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - 111 Dickinson move to 185, 2002; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 2)
    - 185 Nassau St. Offices, 1994-2002; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 3)
    - 250th Anniversary Committee, 1992-1997; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 4)
    - Administrative Memos, 1987-1997; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 5)
    - African-American Studies Program, 1986-2002; 5 folders (Box 105, Folder 6-10)
    - Afro-American Studies Party: Simmons/TM Birthday, 1989-1993; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 11)
    - African-American Studies Post-doc Program, 1990-1991; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 12)
    - African-American Studies Post-docs: Fordham and Awkward, 1991; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 13)
    - African-American Studies Post-doc Queries, 1991-1998; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 14)
    - African-American Studies Search Committee, 1999-2000; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 15)
    - Alumni Council, 1989-2003; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 16)
    - American Studies/Anthropology, 1990-1997; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 17)
    - Articles about Princeton's Black Community, 1990-1995; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 18)
    - Athletics/Black Employees Association, 1987-1998; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 19)
    - Building/Furniture Info, 1990-1991; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 20)
    - Chapel, 1990-1998; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 21)
    - Center for Arts and Cultural Policy Studies, 1994-2002; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 22)
    - Center for Human Values, 1994-2004; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 23)
    - Center of International Studies/Institute for Transregional Study, 1995-2000; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 24)
    - Communications, 1987-2001; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 25)
    - Comparative Literature, 1997-1998; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 26)
    - Council of the Humanities, 1988-2010; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 27)
    - Creative Writing, 1987-2005; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 28)
    - Davis Center, 1990-1992; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 29)
    - Dean of the College, 1988-1996; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 30)
    - Dean of the Faculty, 1989-2001; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 31)
    - Development, 1989-2005; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 32)
    - English, 1988-2002; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 33)
    - Graduate College, 1992-1999; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 34)
    - History/Hellenic Studies, 1993-2003; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 35)
    - Homelessness Project, 1991-1992; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 36)
    - Humanities Council, 1989-1994; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 37)
      Includes 3 black and white photographs, dated 1989.
    - Human Resources, 1992; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 38)
    - Library, Mathey College, Near Eastern Studies, 1993-2005; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 39)
    - Miscellaneous, 1987-2011; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 40)
    - Move to Dickinson, 1988-1990; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 41)
    - Moving Preparation, 2001-2002; 1 folder (Box 105, Folder 42)
    - Office Hardware and Equipment, 1989-1992; 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Office Supplies and Expenses, 1989-1991; 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 2)
    - Politics, 1987-1997; 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 3)
    - President/Vice-President, 1989-2010; 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 4)
    - Press, 1987-1997; 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 5)
    - Program in Theater and Dance/Visual Arts, 1990-1994; 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 6)
    - Provost, 1991-2003; 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 7)
    - Religion, 1993-2001; 1 folder (Box 106, Folder 8)